<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>The Energy Whisperer</title>
    <link href="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io" />
    <updated>2025-01-04T11:44:12-03:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Victor Batista</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Best Practices for Cable Tray Design</title>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Batista</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/best-practices-for-cable-tray-design.html"/>
        <id>https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/best-practices-for-cable-tray-design.html</id>
            <category term="Power Cables"/>

        <updated>2025-01-04T11:21:08-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Cable tray design is an essential practice in electrical infrastructure and network projects. It ensures the organization, safety, and efficiency of the system, as well as facilitating maintenance and future expansion. A well-executed design prevents problems such as overloading, interference, and cable damage, and promotes&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Cable tray design is an essential practice in electrical infrastructure and network projects. It ensures the organization, safety, and efficiency of the system, as well as facilitating maintenance and future expansion. A well-executed design prevents problems such as overloading, interference, and cable damage, and promotes a safer and more efficient work environment. In this article, we will discuss best practices for cable tray design, covering everything from initial planning to execution and maintenance.</p>
<figure ><figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/8/bandejamento-de-cabos.jpg" alt="Best Practices for Cable Tray Design" width="603" height="339" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" srcset="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/8/responsive/bandejamento-de-cabos-xs.jpg 640w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/8/responsive/bandejamento-de-cabos-sm.jpg 768w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/8/responsive/bandejamento-de-cabos-md.jpg 1024w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/8/responsive/bandejamento-de-cabos-lg.jpg 1366w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/8/responsive/bandejamento-de-cabos-xl.jpg 1600w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/8/responsive/bandejamento-de-cabos-2xl.jpg 1920w"></figure>
<figcaption >Cable Tray Design</figcaption>
</figure>
<h1>1. Proper Planning</h1>
<p><br>Before beginning the installation, it is crucial to carry out detailed planning. This includes:<br><br>Needs Analysis: Assess the current and future demands of the system to properly size the tray. Consider the type and quantity of cables, as well as expansion needs.<br><br>Project Layout: Develop a layout that optimizes the use of space and facilitates access to the cables. The design should include the location of trays, supports, and cable entry and exit points.<br>Standards and Regulations: Ensure that the project complies with local and international standards and regulations, such as NBR 14565 (Cable Trays and Supports - Requirements and Procedures) and IEC 61537 (Supports for Cable Systems).</p>
<h1>2. Choice of Materials</h1>
<p><br>The selection of materials for the tray must consider several factors:<br><br>Type of Tray: There are different types of trays, such as perforated, solid and cable trays. The choice should be based on the type of cables, the environment and the need for ventilation.<br>Tray Material: Trays can be made of steel, aluminum or plastic. Steel is resistant and ideal for industrial environments, while aluminum is lighter and resistant to corrosion. Plastic trays are recommended for environments with low load and humidity.<br>Accessories: Use quality accessories, such as connectors, supports and fasteners, to ensure the stability and safety of the system.</p>
<h1>3. Proper Installation</h1>
<p>A well-done installation is essential for the system’s performance:<br><br>Spacing and Distance: Maintain adequate distance between trays and other components to ensure ventilation and avoid overloading.<br><br>Cable Management: Organize cables to minimize interference and facilitate access. Use dividers and supports to separate different types of cables, such as power and data.<br><br>Fixing and Support: Trays must be securely fixed, using appropriate supports and respecting the load specifications. Avoid overloading the trays, as this can cause damage to the cables and compromise safety.</p>
<h1>4. Maintenance and Inspection</h1>
<p><br>Regular maintenance is essential to ensure the longevity and efficiency of the tray system:<br><br>Periodic Inspections: Perform regular inspections to check the condition of the trays and cables. Look for signs of wear, corrosion or damage.<br><br>Cleaning: Keep the trays and cables clean and free of debris that can obstruct ventilation or cause other problems.<br><br>Documentation: Maintain detailed documentation of the system, including layout, material specifications, and maintenance records. This makes troubleshooting and future expansion easier.</p>
<h1>Conclusion</h1>
<p><br>Following best practices in cable tray design is essential to ensuring the efficiency, safety, and durability of electrical and network systems. Careful planning, proper selection of materials, proper installation, and regular maintenance are key elements to the success of any project. By adopting these practices, you not only protect your investment in the infrastructure, but also promote a safer and more productive work environment.</p>
<p>#CableTrayDesign #ElectricalInfrastructure #NetworkEngineering #ElectricalSafety #DataCenter #Telecom #Industrial #Construction</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Switch Grounding Grid for Equipotentialization</title>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Batista</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/switch-grounding-grid-for-equipotentialization.html"/>
        <id>https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/switch-grounding-grid-for-equipotentialization.html</id>
            <category term="Grounding Grid"/>

        <updated>2025-01-04T11:15:33-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Small auxiliary meshes are usually used under the disconnector control boxes. The main reason for this network, according to the companies that adopt it, is to reduce the risk of electric shock and protect the operator. In practice, a well-designed mesh for the entire substation&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Small auxiliary meshes are usually used under the disconnector control boxes. The main reason for this network, according to the companies that adopt it, is to reduce the risk of electric shock and protect the operator.</p>
<figure ><figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/7/ground-grid-meash-simulation.jpg" alt="" width="2048" height="998" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" srcset="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/7/responsive/ground-grid-meash-simulation-xs.jpg 640w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/7/responsive/ground-grid-meash-simulation-sm.jpg 768w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/7/responsive/ground-grid-meash-simulation-md.jpg 1024w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/7/responsive/ground-grid-meash-simulation-lg.jpg 1366w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/7/responsive/ground-grid-meash-simulation-xl.jpg 1600w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/7/responsive/ground-grid-meash-simulation-2xl.jpg 1920w"></figure>
<figcaption >Ground Grid simulation for high voltage 500kV Switch mesh - Difference for a grid and soil potential.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>In practice, a well-designed mesh for the entire substation protects people everywhere, even in rainy conditions and without adequate equipment, such as boots or gloves, avoiding direct contact with the gravel and the control box.<br><br>We carried out a brief study to evaluate how this auxiliary network affects the disconnectors in the switchyard and its effects on the risk of electric shock. In the entire substation where the study was carried out, the touch potential was considerably lower, however, the touch potential drops to less than 20 volts in the region where the disconnector auxiliary mesh was adopted.<br><br>#ElectricalSafety #Substations #ElectricShock #WorkSafety<br>#ElectricalEngineering #AuxiliaryNetworks #DisconnectorManeuvers #AccidentPrevention #SafetyEngineering #IndustrialSafety</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>ACCC Conductors: Advancing the Future of Power Transmission</title>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Batista</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/accc-conductors-advancing-the-future-of-power-transmission.html"/>
        <id>https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/accc-conductors-advancing-the-future-of-power-transmission.html</id>
            <category term="Power Cables"/>

        <updated>2025-01-04T10:22:54-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    In the ever-evolving energy sector, ACCC Conductors (Aluminum Conductor Composite Core) have emerged as a cutting-edge solution for modern transmission systems. Let’s break it down: https://ctcglobal.com/accc-conductor/ The cable is compose by: Core: A hybrid carbon and glass fiber composite core bound with high-temperature epoxy resin.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>In the ever-evolving energy sector, ACCC Conductors (Aluminum Conductor Composite Core) have emerged as a cutting-edge solution for modern transmission systems. Let’s break it down:</p>
<p> </p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://cdn-ilchmjj.nitrocdn.com/xeRXXNKHGwCbVBJkIsGSKRKZwvnVIzXW/assets/images/optimized/rev-a7aba62/ctcglobal.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/ACCC%C2%AE-Conductor-e1689808205951.webp" alt="https://ctcglobal.com/accc-conductor/" width="143" height="400" data-is-external-image="true"></figure>
<p class="align-center"><em><a href="https://ctcglobal.com/accc-conductor/">https://ctcglobal.com/accc-conductor/</a></em></p>
<address> </address>
<p>The cable is compose by: Core: A hybrid carbon and glass fiber composite core bound with high-temperature epoxy resin. This core offers exceptional tensile strength and elasticity. Aluminum Strands: Trapezoidal, high-conductivity aluminum strands surround the core, maximizing conductivity and minimizing electrical resistance.</p>
<p>This cable is a corrosion Resistance: High-grade boron-free glass fibers enhance flexibility and toughness, preventing galvanic corrosion between the core and aluminum strands.</p>
<h3>Utility:</h3>
<p><br>The composite core carries the mechanical load, while the aluminum strands conduct electricity efficiently. The design ensures:<br><br>Reduced Sag: The lower coefficient of thermal expansion minimizes sag, even under high temperatures.<br><br>Enhanced Efficiency: Lighter weight and high strength allow for increased spans between fewer or shorter structures, reducing upfront capital costs and environmental impact.<br><br>Increased Capacity: With the ability to withstand higher temperatures, ACCC conductors can carry up to twice the current of ACSR conductors.</p>
<h3>Advantages:</h3>
<p><br>The ACCC conductor stands out for several reasons:<br><br>Increased Line Capacity: Ideal for increasing the capacity of existing lines without modifying or replacing structures.<br><br>Greater Strength, Reduced Sag: The hybrid carbon composite core is 40% stronger and 70% lighter than steel, reducing sag at high temperatures and resisting degradation from environmental factors.<br><br>Reduction in Capital Expenditures: Fewer or shorter structures required, reducing project costs, construction time, and environmental impacts.<br><br>System Efficiency: Reduces line losses by 25%-40%, freeing up generation capacity and reducing fuel consumption and emissions.</p>
<h3>Applications</h3>
<p><br>ACCC conductors are revolutionizing power systems globally:<br>Upgrading Aging Infrastructure: Enhances capacity without significant structural changes.<br><br>Renewable Energy Integration: Supports high-capacity lines for solar and wind power.<br><br>Urban Transmission: Ideal for densely populated areas where space constraints demand high-capacity, low-sag solutions.<br><br>Grid Modernization: Key to building smarter, more efficient energy networks.<br><br>As we strive for a sustainable energy future, advanced technologies like ACCC conductors are pivotal. They address the challenges of growing demand and aging infrastructure while aligning with global goals for efficiency and carbon footprint reduction.</p>
<p><span aria-hidden="true">#</span>EnergyInnovation <span aria-hidden="true">#</span>PowerTransmission <span aria-hidden="true">#</span>ACCCConductors <span aria-hidden="true">#</span>RenewableEnergy <span aria-hidden="true">#</span>Sustainability</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Understanding Touch Potential in Substation External Fences: Importance for Safety and Compliance</title>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Batista</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/understanding-touch-potential-in-substation-external-fences-importance-for-safety-and-compliance.html"/>
        <id>https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/understanding-touch-potential-in-substation-external-fences-importance-for-safety-and-compliance.html</id>
            <category term="Grounding Grid"/>

        <updated>2025-01-04T09:55:24-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Safety in electrical installations is a perennial concern, especially when it comes to substations and their external fencing. A crucial aspect of this safety is the management of touch potential on fences, which can impact the safety of personnel and the integrity of operations. Let’s&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Safety in electrical installations is a perennial concern, especially when it comes to substations and their external fencing. A crucial aspect of this safety is the management of touch potential on fences, which can impact the safety of personnel and the integrity of operations. Let’s explore how ground potential rise and touch potential can affect external fencing and the importance of following the standards to ensure safety.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/5/1724018581724.png" alt="" width="800" height="450" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" srcset="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/5/responsive/1724018581724-xs.png 640w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/5/responsive/1724018581724-sm.png 768w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/5/responsive/1724018581724-md.png 1024w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/5/responsive/1724018581724-lg.png 1366w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/5/responsive/1724018581724-xl.png 1600w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/5/responsive/1724018581724-2xl.png 1920w"></figure>
<p> </p>
<h2>The Impact of Ground Potential on External Fencing</h2>
<p>When a short circuit occurs in a substation, the ground potential rise can extend beyond the area immediately enclosed by the main grid. This means that the area surrounding the substation can experience a significant ground potential rise, which can extend hundreds of meters beyond the grounding conductors. This phenomenon is crucial to understanding how safety should be managed around substation external fencing.</p>
<h2>Touch Potential: What You Need to Know</h2>
<p>External fencing, often referred to as perimeter fencing or property fencing, can present a significant touch potential. When touching the fence, the potential difference between the metal part of the fence and the ground can cause risks. According to NBR 15751, it is essential to evaluate the potential for touch considering the situation in which a person touches the fence while standing 1 meter away from a grounding point.<br><br>If the fence is grounded at multiple points, a varied potential for touch may arise along the fence due to a short circuit. To ensure safety, the highest possible potential for touch between the grounding points must be considered.</p>
<h2><figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/5/1724018663446.png" alt="" width="1061" height="1500" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" srcset="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/5/responsive/1724018663446-xs.png 640w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/5/responsive/1724018663446-sm.png 768w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/5/responsive/1724018663446-md.png 1024w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/5/responsive/1724018663446-lg.png 1366w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/5/responsive/1724018663446-xl.png 1600w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/5/responsive/1724018663446-2xl.png 1920w"></figure>Importance of Compliance and Preventative Measures</h2>
<p>Ensuring that external fences are properly grounded and that the touch potential is properly assessed is crucial to the safety of any electrical installation. Following standards and recommended practices, such as those established in NBR 15751, helps prevent accidents and protect both workers and the general public.<br><br>Safety in electrical installations is an aspect that should not be neglected. Understanding and correctly applying grounding standards and touch potential assessment are essential to maintaining a safe and regulatory-compliant environment.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Maintaining safety on the external fences of substations is vital to the protection of everyone involved. Adopting best practices and following established standards ensures not only compliance, but also operational safety. Always be aware of guidelines and potential assessments to protect your team and the community.<br><br>🔌⚡ #ElectricalSafety #ElectricalEngineering #Substations #Grounding #TechnicalStandards #NBR15751 #ElectricalProtection #SafetyEngineering</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>🔍 Touch Potential Analysis of Insulated Fences: An Important Step for Safety 🔍</title>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Batista</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/touch-potential-analysis-of-insulated-fences-an-important-step-for-safety.html"/>
        <id>https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/touch-potential-analysis-of-insulated-fences-an-important-step-for-safety.html</id>
            <category term="Grounding Grid"/>

        <updated>2025-01-04T09:50:23-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    For a complete study of the touch potential of insulated fences, it is crucial to evaluate the simultaneous touch between different parts of the fence. The following image illustrates a scenario where a person can touch two insulated parts of the fence during a short&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>For a complete study of the touch potential of insulated fences, it is crucial to evaluate the simultaneous touch between different parts of the fence. <br>The following image illustrates a scenario where a person can touch two insulated parts of the fence during a short circuit. These parts may be subject to different potentials due to the nature of the event. </p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/4/cerca-energizada.jpg" alt="fenece touch potencial scheme" width="1280" height="1706" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" srcset="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/cerca-energizada-xs.jpg 640w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/cerca-energizada-sm.jpg 768w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/cerca-energizada-md.jpg 1024w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/cerca-energizada-lg.jpg 1366w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/cerca-energizada-xl.jpg 1600w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/cerca-energizada-2xl.jpg 1920w"></figure>Based on the assumption that the fence will be grounded at the indicated points, during a short circuit in the substation, the fence will assume a potential compatible with the highest potential found at the grounding rods.<br>Therefore, the potential difference between adjacent segments of the fence must be less than the tolerable limit, as calculated by the IEEE 80 standard. This ensures safety and compliance with the required standards. </p>
<p><br>#ElectricalSafety #IEEEStandards #ElectricalEngineering #InsulatedFences #ShortCircuit #Grounding</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Lightning strikes vs. Density of atmospheric discharges</title>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Batista</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/lightning-strikes-vs-density-of-atmospheric-discharges.html"/>
        <id>https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/lightning-strikes-vs-density-of-atmospheric-discharges.html</id>
            <category term="Lightning"/>

        <updated>2025-01-04T09:48:07-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Lightning strikes are the phenomenon over which we have the least control in engineering projects. Their incidence and frequency vary considerably around the world. In countries such as Brazil, close to the equator, their occurrence is up to ten times greater than in mid-latitudes and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Lightning strikes are the phenomenon over which we have the least control in engineering projects. Their incidence and frequency vary considerably around the world. In countries such as Brazil, close to the equator, their occurrence is up to ten times greater than in mid-latitudes and also ten times more frequent over continents than over oceans.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/v2/D4D22AQE1sxiUvKKvLQ/feedshare-shrink_800/feedshare-shrink_800/0/1724598220078?e=1738800000&amp;v=beta&amp;t=ZeLNe79NKdHGiArMmY44T5Nyd2qa8i8tMlfF6gHs8Jo" alt="Image preview" data-is-external-image="true"></p>
<p>Traditionally, the keraunic index is used to assess the amount of lightning in a location, measuring the number of days with storms in the year, Td, the number of days with thunderstorms. However, the keraunic index has limitations, as it does not reflect the amount of cloud-to-ground lightning, the most relevant parameter for sizing lightning protection systems.<br><br>Currently, there are more accurate methods for characterizing lightning strikes. These methods use advanced systems that, in addition to counting the lightning that hits the ground, identify other important parameters, such as the time and location of the impact, the intensity and polarity of the main discharge, the number and intensity of subsequent discharges, and the waveforms. These systems employ a wide range of technologies, from simple spark gaps and magnetic recorders installed on tall structures to sophisticated equipment for monitoring electric and magnetic fields.<br><br>The density of atmospheric discharges to the earth (Ng = atmospheric discharges/km²/year) defines the annual number of discharges that occur in a given region. The probability of a structure being struck by lightning in a year is calculated by multiplying the discharge density by the size of the exposed area of ​​the structure.<br><br>Annex F of the NBR-5419 standard provides maps of the Density of Atmospheric Discharges (Ng) for Brazil and its regions. These maps were prepared based on records of light pulses captured by the Lightning Imaging Sensor (LIS) on board NASA's Tropical Rainfall Measuring Mission (TRMM) satellite, during the period from 1998 to 2009. This same map is made available by the ONS for studies of basic design of lines and substations.<br><br>The correlation between the keraunic index (Td) and the discharge density (Ng) can be established by empirical formulas specific to each region, based on statistical surveys. According to NBR-5419, for temperate regions, the relationship between Ng and Td is approximately Ng ≈ 0.1 Td.</p>
<p>#AtmosphericDischarges #LightningSafety #DischargeProtection #StandardNBR5419 #MeteorologicalAnalysis<br>#MonitoringTechnology #ProtectionSystems #LightningAndDischarges<br>#RiskManagement #ElectricalEngineering #AtmosphericSciences #DischargeMaps #LightningMonitoring #StructureSafety<br>#MeteorologicalData</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title> Grounding Grid: Analysis grid discretization</title>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Batista</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/grounding-grid-analysis-grid-discretization.html"/>
        <id>https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/grounding-grid-analysis-grid-discretization.html</id>
            <category term="Grounding Grid"/>

        <updated>2025-01-02T17:14:23-03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    The solution in grounding grid analysis depends directly on the grid discretization. The smaller the segment, the more faithful the representation of reality. In this study, I simulated a 100x100m grid with 10x10m grids with different segment sizes. The graph shows that reducing the segment&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p>
    The solution in grounding grid analysis depends directly on the grid discretization. The smaller the segment, the more faithful the representation of reality.<br><br>In this study, I simulated a 100x100m grid with 10x10m grids with different segment sizes. The graph shows that reducing the segment size leads to a more uniform voltage distribution that is closer to the real value.
  </p>

  <p>
    
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/2/1.jpg" height="967" width="1920" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" srcset="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/2/responsive/1-xs.jpg 640w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/2/responsive/1-sm.jpg 768w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/2/responsive/1-md.jpg 1024w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/2/responsive/1-lg.jpg 1366w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/2/responsive/1-xl.jpg 1600w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/2/responsive/1-2xl.jpg 1920w">
      
    </figure>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/2/2.jpg" height="967" width="1920" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" srcset="https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/2/responsive/2-xs.jpg 640w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/2/responsive/2-sm.jpg 768w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/2/responsive/2-md.jpg 1024w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/2/responsive/2-lg.jpg 1366w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/2/responsive/2-xl.jpg 1600w ,https://TheEnergyWhisperer.github.io/media/posts/2/responsive/2-2xl.jpg 1920w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    #engenhariaelétrica #malhadeaterramento #simulação #análise #eletromagnetismo
  </p>

  <p>
    #electricalengineering #earthingmesh #simulation #analysis #electromagnetism
  </p>

  <p>
    
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
